Guide to the Sino-Japanese and Russo-Japanese War Prints Collection 10142303
C. V. Starr East Asian Library
- Series II: Russo-Japanese War Prints/日露戦争錦絵, 1904-1905
  - 陸戦第一日本軍大勝利 定州南門外ニ於テ黒川大尉奮戦ノ図 = Rikusen daiichi Nihon gun daishōri: Teishū Nanmon-gai ni oite Kurokawa Taii funsen no zu, 明治37年3月20日, Meiji 37 [1904 March 20] (Mapcase A5, Item 058)
    絵師/Artist: 年英 Toshihide. Full name: 右田年英 Migita, Toshihide, 1863 or 1862-1925. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Matsuno Yonejirō. 出版者: 松野米次郎. Geographical Subject: 定州 Teishū
  - 我騎兵隊ノ将校斥候 定州南門附近ニ於テ 頑強ナル敵之砲火ニ應ジ 勇闘猛戦 竟ニ之ヲ撃退定州ヲ占領ス（我騎兵隊将校斥候於定州南門附近應頑強敵之砲火勇闘猛戦竟撃退之占領定州） = Waga kiheitai no shōkō sekkō Teishū Nanmon fukin ni oite gankyōnaru teki no hōka ni ōji yūtō mōsen tsuini kore o gekitai Teishū o senryō su = In the vicinity of the South Gate of Dingzhou commissioned officer scouts of our cavalry faced heavy enemy fire, and engaged in valiant struggle and savage fighting. Finally overcoming resistance they occupied Dingzhou, 明治37, Meiji 37 [1904]? (Mapcase A5, Item 077)
    絵師/Artist: 月三 Gessan.
  - 懲露義戦仁川海戦 = Chō Ro gisen Jinsen kaisen, 明治37年2月, Meiji 37 [1904 February] (Mapcase A5, Item 079)
    絵師/Artist: 清親 Kiyochika. Also known as: 小林清親 Kobayashi, Kiyochika, 1847-1915. Published: Inoue Kichijirō. 出版者: 井上吉次郎. Geographical Subject: 仁川 Incheon
  - 大喝一聲 第四回旅順攻撃に我駆逐隊中漣艦の一等 ... = Daikatsu issei daiyonkai Ryojun kōgeki ni waga kuchikutaitai chū Sazanami kan no ittō, 明治37年3月19日, Meiji 37 [1904 March 19] (Mapcase A5, Item 080)
    絵師/Artist: 美邦 Yoshikuni. Published: Matsuki Heikichi. 出版者: [松木平吉].
  - 第二軍金州上陸之圖 = Dainigun Kinshū jōriku no zu, 明治37, Meiji 37 [1904] (Mapcase A5, Item 083)
    絵師/Artist: 清親 Kiyochika. Also known as: 小林清親 Kobayashi, Kiyochika, 1847-1915. Geographical Subject: 金州 Kinshiu (Halbinsel Liau-tung)
  - 第四回の旅順攻撃 = Daiyonkai no Ryojun kōgeki, 明治37年3月21日, Meiji 37 [1904 March 21] (Mapcase A5, Item 084)
    絵師/Artist: 柳蛙 Ryūa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Tsunejirō. 出版者: 長谷川常治郎. Geographical Subject: 旅順 Port Arthur
  - 軍神我海軍中佐廣瀬武夫君 = Gunshin waga kaigun chūsa Hirose Takeo-kun, 明治37年5月1日, Meiji 37 [1904 May 01] (Mapcase A5, Item 085)
    絵師/Artist: 耕漁 Kōgyo. Also known as: 月岡耕漁 Tsukioka, Kōgyo; 坂巻耕漁, Sakamaki, Kōgyo, 1869-1927. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Kimura, Toyokichi. 出版者: 木村豊吉. Geographical Subject: 旅順 Port Arthur
  - 仁川港ニ於テ我艦敵艦二隻ヲ撃沈敗兵端艇ニ乗ジテ逃走スル之図（於仁川港我艦撃沈敵艦ニ = Jinsen kō ni oite waga kan tekikan niseki o gekichin haihei tantei ni jōjite tōsō suru no zu, 明治37年2月, Meiji 37 [1904 February] (Mapcase A5, Item 086)
    絵師/Artist: 華香 Kakō. Also known as: 森田華香 Morita, Kakō, 1870-1931?. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Matsuki Heikichi. 出版者: 松本平吉. Geographical Subject: 仁川 Incheon
  - 日本全勝九連城占領之図 = Nihon zenshō Kurenjō senryō no zu, 明治37年5月17日, Meiji 37 [1904 May 17] (Mapcase A5, Item 087)
    絵師/Artist: 年光 Toshimitsu. Full name: 進斎年光 Shinsai, Toshimitsu. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Matsuno Yonejirō. 出版者: 松野米次郎. Geographical Subject: 九連城 Kurenjō Jiuliancheng
  - 日露京城ノ攻撃大日本大勝利帝国萬歳 = Nichi-Ro Keijō no kōgeki Dai Nihon daishōri teikoku banzai = The great victory of the Japanese army in Seoul engagement, 明治37年2月, Meiji 37 [1904 February] (Mapcase A5, Item 088)
    絵師/Artist: 柳蛙 Ryūa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Fukuda Hatsujirō. 出版者: 福田初次郎. Geographical Subject: 京城 Seoul
  - 日露交戦画報 其三 京城之戦報 = Nichi-Ro kōsen gahō. Sono san Keijō no senpō = The great victory of the Japanese army in Seoul engagement, 明治37年2月, Meiji 37 [1904 February] (Mapcase A5, Item 089)
    絵師/Artist: 延一 Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Sonokichi. 出版者: 長谷川園吉 (彫榮). Geographical Subject: 京城 Seoul
  - 日露旅順口海戦水雷艇成功之図 = Nichi-Ro Ryojunkō kaisen suiraitei seikō no zu, 明治37年2月, Meiji 37 [1904 February] (Mapcase A5, Item 090)
    絵師/Artist: 珍齋呂雪 Chinsai Rosetsu. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Katada Chōjirō. 出版者: 片田長次郎. Geographical Subject: 旅順 Port Arthur
  - 日露戦報於第二旅順襲撃速鳥朝霧勇戦図 = Nichi-Ro senpō Daini Ryojun Shūgeki ni oite sokuchō Asagiri yūsen zu, 明治37, [Meiji 37] [1904] (Mapcase A5, Item 091)
    絵師/Artist: 静斎？ Seisai. Published: Tokyo, Japan. Geographical Subject: 旅順 Port Arthur
  - 鴨緑江附近露軍撃退之圖 = Ōryokukō fukin Ro-gun gekitai no zu = Driving Back Russian Forces in the Vicinity of the Yalu River, 明治37年2月20日？, Meiji 37 [1904 February 20?] (Mapcase A5, Item 092)
    絵師/Artist: 延一 Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Tsunejirō. 出版者: 長谷川常治郎. Geographical Subject: 鴨緑江 Yalu River, Amnok-kang
    Also see CLIO record
  - 旅順大海戦露艦撃沈之図 = Ryojun daikaisen Ro kan gekichin no zu, 明治37, [Meiji 37] [1904] (Mapcase A5, Item 093)
    絵師/Artist: 華香 Kakō. Also known as: 森田華香 Morita, Kakō, 1870-1931?. Geographical Subject: 旅順 Port Arthur
  - 旅順港閉塞隊廣瀬中佐奮戦 = Ryojunkō Heisokutai Hirose Chūsa funsen, 明治37年5月刊, Meiji 37 [1904 May] (Mapcase A5, Item 094)
    絵師/Artist: 鏡湖 Kyōko. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Fukuda Hatsujirō. 出版者: 福田初次郎. Geographical Subject: 旅順 Port Arthur
  - 旅順港海戦第一軍巧者南沢安雄君… :明治三七年三月十日暁 = Ryojunkō kaisen Daiichigun kōsha Minamizawa Yasuo-kun… Meiji sanjūshichinen Sangatsu tōka akatsuki, 明治37年4月１1日, Meiji 37 [1904 April 11] (Mapcase A5, Item 095)
    絵師/Artist: 耕漁 Kōgyo. Also known as: 月岡耕漁 Tsukioka, Kōgyo; 坂巻耕漁, Sakamaki, Kōgyo, 1869-1927. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Kimura Toyokichi. 出版者: 木村豊吉. Geographical Subject: 旅順 Port Arthur
  - 敵ノ旗艦自ラ水雷ニ触レテ沈没シ麻可露夫提督以下乗員八百魚腹ニ葬ラル (敵旗艦自触水雷沈没麻可露夫提督以下乗員八百葬魚腹) = Teki no kikan mizukara suirai ni furete chinbotsu shi Makarofu Teitoku ika jōin happyaku gyofuku ni hōmuraru, 明治37年5月, Meiji 37 [1904 May] (Mapcase A5, Item 096)
    絵師/Artist: 耕挙 Kōkyo. Also known as: 原田耕挙 Harada, Kōkyo, 1863-1925 (active 1894-1904). Published: Tokyo, Japan, Matsumoto Heikichi. 出版者: 松本平吉.
  - 我第二軍砲雷弾再ヲ冐シテ蓋平之地ヲ占領ス = Waga Dainigun hōraidan sai o okashite Gaihei no chi o senryō su, 明治37年7月, Meiji 37 [1904 July] (Mapcase A5, Item 097)
    絵師/Artist: 美邦 Yoshikuni. Also known as: 野村美邦 Nomura, Yoshikuni. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Matsumoto Heikichi. 出版者: 松本平吉. Geographical Subject: 蓋平 Gàizhōu
  - 我軍鳳凰城占領ス大日本陸軍大勝利万歳 = Waga gun Hōōjō senryō su Dai Nihon Rikugun daishōri banzai = Japanese army capturing Fuinhunchen, 明治37, Meiji 37 [1904] (Mapcase A5, Item 098)
    絵師/Artist: 輝方 Terukata. Also known as: 池田輝方 Ikeda, Terukata, 1883-1921. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Fukuda Hatsujirō. 出版者: 福田初次郎. Geographical Subject: 鳳凰城 Fuinhunchen
  - 我軍猛進シテ旅順ノ背面ヲ攻撃ス（我軍猛進シテ攻撃旅順ノ背面ヲ） = Waga fun mōshin shite Ryojun no haimen o kōgeki su, 明治37, Meiji 37 [1904] (Mapcase A5, Item 099)
    絵師/Artist: 美邦 Yoshikuni. Also known as: 野村美邦 Nomura, Yoshikuni. Geographical Subject: 旅順 Port Arthur
  - 我艦隊二月九日仁川港ニ露艦ワリヤーグ コレーツニ隻ヲ轟沈セシム = Waga kantai nigatsu kokonoka Jinsenkō ni Ro kan Wariyāgu Korētsu niseki o gōchin seshimu = In Russo-Japanese War at Chinmulpo on Tuesday (1904 February 9th) Our Squadron destroyed the Russian cruiser "Wariyag" and the gunboat "Colech", 明治37年2月, Meiji 37 [1904 February] (Mapcase A5, Item 100)
    絵師/Artist: 年英 Toshihide. Full name: 右田年英 Migita, Toshihide, 1863 or 1862-1925. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Akiyama Takeemon. 出版者: 秋山武右衛門. Geographical Subject: 仁川 Incheon
  - 我漣艦捕獲並敵艦漏水ノ為沈没セント将ニ我艦之勇兵険ヲ冐シテ軍旗ヲ撤厺スル之図于時明治三十七年三月十日 = Waga Nagisa kan hokaku narabini tekikan rōsui no tame chinbotsu sento masani waga kan no yūhei ken o okashite gunki o tekkyo suru no zu tokini Meiji sanjūshichinen Sangatsu tōka, 明治37, Meiji 37 [1904] (Mapcase A5, Item 101)
    絵師/Artist: 耕挙 Kōkyo. Also known as: 原田耕挙 Harada, Kōkyo, 1863-1925 (active 1894-1904).
  - 日露海戦勲功美譚之内: 旅順港閉塞隊 広瀬海軍中佐奇勲 決死隊指揮長 = Nichi-Ro kaisen kunkō bitan no uchi: Ryojunkō Heisokutai Hirose kaigun chūsa kikun kesshitai shikichō = Blockade of Port Arthur under the Command of Naval Captain Hirose, 明治37, Meiji 37 [1904] (Mapcase A5, Item 109)
    絵師/Artist: 蝸堂 Kadō. is Also know as: 稲垣蝸堂 Inagaki, Kadō. Geographical Subject: 旅順港 Port Arthur
  - 日露戦争名誉軍人鑑 = Nichi-Ro Sensō meiyo gunjin kagami = Honored Military Officers of the Russo-Japanese War, 明治37, Meiji 37 [1904] (Mapcase A5, Item 110)
    Published: Tokyo, Japan, Kida Asajirō. 出版者: 木田淺次郎.
- Series III: Other Prints, 1864-1892
  - 憲法発布式御出門之図 = Kenpō Happu shiki goshutsumon no zu, 明治22年2月20日, Meiji 20 [1887 February 20] (Mapcase A5, Item 102)
    絵師/Artist: 幾英 Ikuhide. Also known as: 小林幾英 Kobayashi, Ikuhide; 小林英次郎 Kobayashi, Eijiro (active 1885-1898). Published: Tokyo, Japan, Yokoyama Enshō. 出版者: 横山園松.
  - 皇居御出門之図 = Kōkyo goshutsumon no zu, 明治22, Meiji 22 [1889] (Mapcase A5, Item 103)
    絵師/Artist: 楊洲周延 Yōshū Chikanobu. Also known as: 豊原周延 Toyohara Chikanobu, 楊洲 Yōshū, 橋本周延 Hashimoto Chikanobu, 橋本直義 Hashimoto Naoyoshi, 楊洲直義 Yōshū Naoyoshi, 1838-1912. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Inoue Mohē. 出版者: 井上茂兵エ.
  - 源義經出陣之圖 = Minamoto Yoshitsune shutsujin no zu, 元治元年, Genji 1 [1864] (Mapcase A5, Item 104)
    絵師/Artist: 芳虎 Yoshitora. Also known as: 孟斎(歌川)芳虎 Mōsai (Utagawa), Yoshitora. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Iseya Kanekichi. 出版者: 伊勢兼 [伊瀬屋兼吉].
  - 大坂平野合戦真田幸村地雷火をもって関東の大軍を破る = Ōsaka Heiya kassen Sanada Yukimura jiraika o motte Kantō no taigun o yaburu, 明治25年5月, Meiji 25 [1892 May] (Mapcase A5, Item 105)
    絵師/Artist: 芳虎 Yoshitora. Also known as: 孟斎(歌川)芳虎 Mōsai (Utagawa), Yoshitora. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Fukuda Kumajirō. 出版者: 福田熊治郎. Geographical Subject: 大坂 Osaka
  - 大手之大将 小野好古 搦手之大将 源經基大 軍ヲ以テ前 伊豫掾純 友居城責 = Ōte no Taishō Ono no Yoshifuru Karamete no Taishō Minamoto no Tsunemoto taigun o motte Saki no Iyo no Jōsumi tomo ga kyojō o semuru, 元治元年, Genji 1 [1864] (Mapcase A5, Item 106)
  - 東京名所上野公園東照宮之真図 = Tōkyō meisho Ueno Kōen Tōshōgū no shinzu, 明治13, Meiji 13 [1880] (Mapcase A5, Item 107)
    絵師/Artist: 廣重[三代目] Hiroshige III. Also known as: 三代目 歌川広重 Utagawa, Hiroshige, III, 1842?-1894. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Yamamoto Yoichi. 出版者: 山本與一. Geographical Subject: Ueno Park, Tokyo